how's that for a thumbnail should I do
that
thumbnail pulling my hair out I out no
more hair left to pull
out all right that's enough of
that I mean that's enough of that there
is not chat on the screen there is just
a YouTube video as
usual uh I'm going to start the video by
saying what we're going to try to do
there is no promise that this video is
going to have anything to do with what I
say at the beginning of the video I'm I
I refuse to promise you
that so this is going to tell you what
we're going to try to do and then you
can and by if you really want to know
what the video is about go to the end
yeah go to the end go to the end of the
video and play like that that little
part of the end where we go okay this is
what we actually got
done um I don't know how long this video
be going to be it's going to be uh less
than two hours though for sure because
I'm going to be leaving to go do the
bike thing but here's the thing Harbor
we need to get Harbor installed
um uh I've already got some of this to
work elsewhere and I've already I've
already been working with Harbor in our
Dev
environments
um
but despite my better judgment I'm going
to go go forward and I'm going to
pretend like I've never insulted Harbor
and we're going to take it again there's
several videos of me starting up trying
to do St Harbor and then regrouping and
doing it again and a lot of the reasons
for that is because we've changed our
Direction based on stuff that we
discovered while we were going through
Harbor and I will talk about that when
we're going to go through this this is
going to be a talkie talkie video
there's going to be a lot of me chatting
uh mostly though it's just going to be
Bubblehead Rob and U the screen and
terminal and all that uh in terms of
like where we're going to install Harbor
we the goal today is going to be to set
it up in
my um my desktop here my VM I've got 8 8
gigabytes um of ram dedicated
to uh a VM on there Anon that I've been
using for a while and it is it is
straight up Linux so um it should
work yeah mini we're talking about a
mini Cube installation uh for those of
you who want to know what happened to my
server it is
dead um I did a whole video about what I
was going to do in the lab I do not have
the money right now uh to go buy a new
server so if you want to follow that you
can but that means I'm going to be
trying to install it in mini Cube and
you know if I can't do it I can't do it
if if that means we go back to the dev
environment fine but I do like to see if
these things are possible so we're going
to try one more time to do mini Cube
that means I'm going to have to do a
little bit of mini Cube setup um there
are so many better people to go to to
learn how to do this up front than me so
you know if you want to stay around and
suffer with me because you're a beginner
um that's great go for it um there have
been a lot of things that have changed
and um so this is going to be a process
of discovery for me as well I again I
already got it to work in the dev
environment and now we're trying to do
it with a different
version
um so we'll see what happens with that
by the way
before we get too far into this um I did
want to tell you an architectural
conclusion that we made on our team
which is not proprietary information
that I think is valuable for a lot of
teams out there um and I'm going to
describe the situation so this is kind
of a storytime situation and I want to
tell you how we concluded and why we
concluded the way we did and I do not
think we're giving away any secrets here
so I'm going to go ahead and share this
so um some time ago
a couple years ago uh the idea of
putting up a different registry we got
off of whatever the other one was I
can't remember even now and
um I'm trying to remember the name but I
can't and so we decided to go with
Harbor and there was some talk back and
forth about getting Harbor up and whe
how long it would take and you know our
clusters were getting kind of
outdated and then we decided to put in
Harbor and there was a little bit of
talk about who would put it in and stuff
and my teammate took it on on and and
and just you know spun it up as fast as
possible and and that is that's what
we're been running on now and we've
since run into a bunch of conclusions
about Harbor at least that version and
um so two really important drivers for
the reason that we're going with the
latest Harbor which is 211 2.11 as of
this video um and the first one is that
uh
Harbor uh ha
uh did not work as designed as it was
advertised and um we I I didn't do this
but they did it and they installed uh
postgress in an ha scenario and
everything and got Harbor running and
then there were components of Harbor
that had no clue about the ha capability
of postr even though we were following
you know log step every step of the way
to get it to work and and that we had
peer riew come in and they confirmed
that that's not the case that it was
that the at least on the
2.5 version of Harbor that the idea of
using ha postgress is completely
negated
by what I would call Design flaws in
2.5S implementation of Harbor itself and
so that led us to have to backtrack on
that actually the reason the the reason
this is relevant is because based on
what they were selling us Harbor was
selling Us in
2.5 um you could get this really intense
you know great ha High availability
Thing by spinning up an independent
postgress and spinning up an independent
redus and we still have a got Redd to
work in 2.5 it's totally
broken and so
we learned a lot about that in fact
there was a bunch of other stuff stuff
going on at the same time including a
cluster migration so our clusters are
getting upgraded and they're getting
spun up automatically with anible and a
bunch of other really cool things that
I'm not directly involved in but so my
task is to get this up because there's
another big bonus here and that is the
security of the latest postgress and um
that has been a driver now all of this
stuff is you know the firewall and
everything it's not like it would be a
security vulnerability at our shop uh at
all uh but there is a desire to get us
on the latest postest right so one of
the reasons that I'm making another
video about this is because after making
the last video and coming coming to a
bunch of conclusions including one very
very important conclusion and that is if
you have to go from 2.5 to 2.6 2.7 and 8
and stuff like that um someplace along
the way and I think it's 27 28 I think
there's at least three of them there are
substantial database migrations and
there are substantial database
requirements and uh someplace along the
way between 2.5 and
2.11 um there is also a more it seems to
be I mean this is one of the things we
have to prove here there is a more
robust
um implementation of the builtin
postgress all right now something else
we need to talk about here is that I
went out
to check on the charts that we're going
to use we flattening Helm charts and
most people will say yeah go get the
bitnami chart and flatten it that's
pretty much the way to go for
anything um but in the process I lost
several hours
um running down the go Harbor Rabbit
Hole so there is there is a uh Helm
chart in go
Harbor and uh let's see if we can find
it
Helm let's
[Music]
see upgrading let's see it might even be
the point is I'm just going to keep
summarizing here so the the helm chart
there are references to the helm chart
on go Harbor and there are references to
the helm chart on vietnami on the same
documentation site and I did an
exhaustive comparison of the two charts
and determined that the bitnami charts
seem to be much more robust um they
include uh integration hooks for uh
external secrets and I could be getting
this wrong but and they they we're going
to find out all this this is kind of out
in what we're going to do and it
included um substantially very clearly
the vietnami stuff includes the embedded
postgress and the embedded redus by that
what I mean is that it has a built-in
postgress deployment as a part of the
chart so that means that postr goes into
to the same namespace and everything and
even though in our current 2.5
implementation of Harbor we
don't we have an external post
and an external
redus uh which isn't working but the
postgress is working still in the same
name space as Harbor but it's managed
entirely separately has its own
installer and everything so what we want
to do I mean and that was that was based
on the recommendations as we understood
them at the time uh I wasn't involved in
an installation but I'm summarizing what
I've heard um that the postgress
installation had to be independent right
you couldn't use the builtin uh
postgress installation I'm not even
completely sure there even is a a
buil-in postgress
installation uh for 2.5 because the only
chart for 2.5 that I looked at initially
was the go Harbor chart and I'm pretty
sure that didn't have it uh and then I
went I was comparing that to vietnami
and I was actually comparing
21s and the um the the the if I remember
this right the um the 2. the the
vietnami charts do have uh what seems to
be a much better Helm chart uh than the
one even on go Harbor um and I am not
going to rant you know you can put a
bullet in there but I am not going to
rant about the fact that there is a
bitnami chart and there is a go Harbor
chart and the nobody knows which one's
authoritative depends on who you ask
right and that bothers me I don't like
that so our team has decided and um this
is this is leading into the actual work
I'm going to be be doing here um our
team has decided that we are very
definitely going to stay with the
bitnami chart because that's what we
already know and we are going to we're
going to flatten that chart into a
template um and then we're going to use
customize uh from the command line to
change out the pieces we need and
eventually uh layer in and overlay uh
with our uh our vault secrets and that's
that's what we use and so uh that is the
goal that is the goal here is to create
a a a build script uh that creates those
those customized
manifests um and then a deploy script
which um takes you know basically does a
qtl apply on those uh manifests after
they've been uh customized um so and I'm
very Rusty on all of this stuff so I'm
just going to tell you right now I am
not an authority on this I in fact as
many people that are here in the chat
who want to help me um you know you're
helping be well appreciated as we go
through this um and and that's why I'm
streaming it because uh hopefully
somebody will be will learn something
when they catch me doing something
stupid um this is a really big deal uh
it's one of the reasons I'm also
streaming it is as many eyes as possible
on this it's obviously going to go
through extensive peer-review of work
but um the more eyes the better I don't
we don't want to deploy another hobbled
you know Harbor registry that we then
have to do so the last conclusion about
our architectural decisions this is a
big one this is a really really big one
um and I I spoke on it I kind of tangent
it off of it when you migrate between
versions 2.5 6 7 8 9 10 11 each time you
go up you need to um use the uh the
template in order to do that and the
template has a database migration built
into it so you need to back up your data
in your posted thing that's also
something we're probably going to write
really quick there's we already have one
so I'm just going to be ripping off that
one um and then we're going to be so you
back up the data obviously right and
then and then you apply the the template
and then you make sure everything works
and then if if it worked then your data
should have been migrated and let that
but get your B database back up to go to
you let that run for a while I I would
suggest and then go to the next version
well you can tell so the the biggest
dilemma here and this is really the
moral of the story do not get behind
because if you get behind six or seven
levels you can't just you know run a
build script that's going to take you
from this version to this version by
flattening the Manifest and letting you
change few values and letting you go you
actually have to do that and and do do
some other things and we actually
created a plan for that using uh our get
repo and and tagging you know different
branches uh for the different increments
and then actually during a change window
doing each one of those all six of them
during the change window which is not
suboptimal because at that point you got
database migrations that you can't
really confirm so you've also got some
sort of systems integration test to
write which we're also going to do uh
we're going to we're going to come up
with some ideas about how to test this
whole thing and make sure that it's
working as intended uh preferably from
the command line but if not through a
written procedure to make sure that all
this stuff is
working um So based on all that uh the
work to do that is significantly more so
uh because that meant that I would have
to flatten each each version all the way
through and then we would have to apply
them incrementally and do a systems test
on each one recovery you know um and
then you know land on 2.11 and hopefully
that we we made it uh the fact that we
are moving to another cluster
and that we have a bunch of leftover old
stuff uh behind and you know users in
the terms of users we've got you know
we've got old users we got old um you
know old repos old containers a bunch of
old data and you know when you're
backing up the postgress database for an
container image registry for HPC ml shop
those images are huge some of them I
mean I can't believe the size of
these kind of like defy the definition
of what a container should actually be
right because they're so big
um so we've decided and I'm just letting
you know we've decided that we are
definitely going to start with 2.11 in a
new fresh clean cluster and we are going
instead of migrating the data we're
going to tell everybody look if you need
help migrating your data let us know but
we're using this as an opportunity
because we got a new cluster we're using
it as an opportunity to clean up that
data we're also using it as an
opportunity to uh use a new user
authentication technique uh which is not
else on the other system and all porting
all of that writing all the code and
doing all the automation testing systems
integation testing to Port all that
would have been a tremendous extra
amount of work so that is not the
primary motivator though the primary
motivator is that we want to get people
used to the new system and we want to
have them using it so this isn't a
copout as much as it is hey we've got
this system and it's new and shiny go
kick it tires and put your stuff over
there and in the process by the way we
were about to go through a cleanup audit
of the previous data and so to to for
that to that end we are going to you
know do this other thing and we got to
create new user accounts anyway with the
new authentication so um a lot of lot of
stuff to take in there uh if you're new
to kubernetes and everything most of the
stuff I said will be absolutely like
unintelligible you have no idea what I'm
talking about um but let's get into it
um Okay so
H am grabbing my mouse I'm not going to
use that that's for sure um okay
so um let's see
here let's change to to to little little
Rob you know what I don't like about
this whole presenter mode thing is that
everything is always backwards you see
that yeah Amazon delay you can't read it
I mean it's fine but it annoys me anyway
um it also because if it was flipped it
would have me like looking like I was
looking at the screen oh well uh I am
sort of at work so I am I might be
distracted on occasion and I'm sorry
there I'm not going to edit the video
because it takes too much time
so just reading some stuff here about
vacation
rotations all right um let's do this so
the we talked about this
already um
and I just set up some zets
here and I should probably get my phone
so I can read the chat let me can you
pause for a second you know what I'll
put some music on I actually no I'll
just go get it I'll put the fishies on
I'm gonna go get I'm GNA go get the uh
my phone so I can actually see your your
guys chat coming in while I'm doing it
um all right
there we
go do I support spark
no data training um container data sizes
uh are the data is large sometimes
people data in
there home lab series this is not home
lab this but we will be
doing some of that um how's the Sound by
the way I should probably have asked
that earlier I'm just I'm using it Lael
mic because it's just easier it's just
much easier for me to
manage um all right so I am kind of
comparing notes
here to some stuff that we've already
got
done um all right
so uh we've actually already started
some of this so so let's see if we can
go find it again I think we had uh Kate
Sapp Harbor always called
right Kap
Harbor um trying to fix the screen so
you can
see all right
so we got our build script here here we
go modernized for latest
kop
um oh and this as you can see you can
see actually let's let's do a little
recap so I've already started this I
think I might have done it in another
video but I'll go ahead and recap really
quick just to remind myself what we're
doing um so let start teamu
here
um
so so we've
got this notion of a Kate app which is
basically you
have uh a read me like this you have a
build
script uh you have a direct directory
with manifest in
it and um you put all your resources in
here so if you've got if you've got like
images that need resources you can put
them in there like that and any any of
your extra dependencies like um tools
and
stuff uh you know scripts that you might
have needed or even sub routines
libraries and stuff like that they go
under Tools um uh the the yams that are
here are just me messing around with
stuff you can see obviously I've got a
different Branch going
on and um there are two other there's
two other things that are not here right
now so let's go ahead and add
those um I can put my face up here how
about that let's
do
[Music]
um uh let's just actually touch those
files really quick so there's going to
be a
deploy and uh an
undeploy and I'm going to just change
those per right now they don't have
anything in
[Music]
them
uh undeploy all right
so that should give us um some stuff hey
thank you for the sub appreciate that I
don't have my notifications on for that
fun stuff like with a little light so
I'll just give you a thumbs up for the
sub how's
that all right so here's the build
deploy
undeploy um so let's let's put something
in those things
uh uh St is in post
yes
um so we're going to use um uh Vin bash
oh oh that reminds me that reminds me we
need to do all this on Linux so um I was
doing this I've been doing this on my
Mac and um we hit some roadblocks and so
you can't do it on a Mac you can't put
Harbor on a Mac
sad day no Harbor on a
Mac wait what where's my rainy day come
on oh well so so let's let's let's not
get too far into this uh get stat
because we're going to be copying it
over oh damn damn all right let's commit
it all commit let's do kit d a DOT and
then
um let's say uh get get
commit uh
uh some
initial scaffolding you know what I
realize I'm probably going to have to do
some setup I'm gonna apologize right now
I'm going to get stuck uh doing a little
bit of Linux setup but it's not horrible
uh my keys are not on this screen I turn
my ass keys off yeah I don't know some
people said they didn't like
them uh do you guys want them back I
mean we should have a vote for the keys
people were saying they they were not a
fan
so yeah what was it called key
Caster just because it's that's Harbor I
didn't make the choice five shot that's
not that's not my choice to make Harbor
is already that made that decision you
don't care about the keys okay yeah I
think I think that's a no I I think it
we'll just I mean I tell you what I'll
turn it on when we do viim someday all
right so uh did we push it
already wait
what get
pushed all right so
um so there we are we we we we did get
push um okay so now we can do the other
thing and some of you I hopefully I
don't get give away the farm here but
some of you know already that I use um
VNC uh actually pay for it I know sue me
I just really love it it's just so
clean um a little bit of a flashbang
there I'm sorry about that
um so this is actually you're looking at
the um at the uh the streamer OBS that I
use when I do my IRL streaming
um which is weird because I just
minimized the Mac thing and really I
need to minimize the windows thing there
we go I know that's like really weird
looking and and I also have this big
screen but behind me thank you now now
we're getting the sound you know why
we're getting the sound 12 is now
following we're getting the sound this
is crazy so think listen to this okay so
we're getting sound now because OBS has
got the plug-in on it and I am real VNC
into the Windows machine which has audio
support that's getting pumped through my
Mac through V real VNC pretty crazy
right so you're like why is this a
Windows machine I don't want to get into
that it's a Windows machine because
Zip's whipped mostly um but we do need
to spin up Anton who you know I thought
about building another um another VM as
a part of the home lab if you want to
see me do that I will do that as a part
of that um Anton is off right now
because um some of my IRL streaming was
getting a little
choppy um and that was kind of causing a
problem you know what's funny is
actually I actually have this screen
right in front of me right now as well
which is just insane uh skip this
version okay so there's there's Anton
Anton's running in the background now
and now we can actually exit out um of
this and uh I'm trying to figure out how
to do that
without okay without killing it here we
go um quit realc VI all right so now
we're no longer tied to real
VNC uh you can actually do everything I
just did with real VNC from your phone
uh I've actually messed with OBS from my
phone while I was on my bike it's pretty
amazing um that's one of the reasons I
pay for it because I like that
reliability I know it's uh you know I
could probably set it all up myself but
I like pay for I've set up BNC servers
before it was years ago so we're looking
again at um at this
machine and we can now SSH into
Anon anton. looc if you don't know about
aahi you know stay tuned we'll go talk
about that some other
day uh we're looking at Anton let's look
at Anton's stats for a
second uh just to give you a sense of it
what Anton is Anton is a abunto machine
VMware I normally I would have this
running on a red hat machine or
something because I do want to get good
with red hat that's what we host on most
of our stuff this is r on until uh it's
I mean it's got It's got lots of stuff
it's only using 512 megabytes of you
know 8 gig of RAM so um so we should be
good to run mini Cube and everything
over here um and uh stuff yeah I don't
know about the Tik Tok thing I don't
know about that um
so anyway so it's I mean everything
you're seeing now is Linux which is
confusing right because I'm actually
streaming from a Mac but now I'm sshed
into a Linux machine which is what I
prefer to do anyway I don't need desktop
Linux I don't care for desktop Linux at
all I streamed from desktop Linux for
two years rant about that another day um
so what are we doing here well first of
all we need to get the repo so I'm going
to CD into
repos uh I may actually already Actually
I don't even need to do that let's see
if I already have it um clone uh Kap
this is my own thing uh Harbor and that
should do it and CD in there that's
actually a
function uh you can there it is right
there you can freeze it and read about
it if you want to understand it and see
how it works it's a really great little
function to have it needs to be a
function not a script because it's going
to CD and that's changing your current
running time runtime environment for
Shell which cannot be done from a script
um so we are in here we uh we can see
what we got here get branch
uh we want to get them all
so um I do see get uh check
out
ah dasp uh it'll tell me which one it is
because I can't remember so modernize
tab um and we'll do that and that'll get
us that should get us here I'm turning
my TV off because it's too
bright there we go hopefully it didn't
kill my computer oh God it's so dark
now it was color correcting okay the
camera's I my camera fixed my color
correction thank
God I was like that weird color okay
so um what do we it's it's not really
performing very well right now
actually yeah it's a little
choppy yeah that's because it's talking
to a VM over my work and that's why it's
choppy that's going to be annoying as
hell
so um that's also actually being caused
by being a VM in
Windows
um
so I'm pausing because I'm actually
seriously
considering I know I should probably
change my view here yeah I'm I'm kind of
seriously
considering um wait where is it there it
is
is that working now I'm seriously
considering
um blowing away what's on this computer
and
putting uh putting all Linux on it again
because I don't have the money for a
server right now even if it's only 700
bucks hey guys I'm streaming in
here thank you this is why I move back
to this room by the way just so you know
I'm thinking of
you I not even kidding that's the reason
I moved back in here because it was so
noisy out there I couldn't stream I
couldn't actually talk so uh NE is good
command
yep no audio is coming from them to the
stream thank God you they're totally
yelling
um so anyway that's all I wanted to say
no server uh This Server will probably
get repurposed as a Linux machine but uh
I need to be careful about doing that
because all all my IRL streaming is is
running through there uh that's a home
lab related issue let back to the topic
in hand um let's do this uh okay
so back to the
Shell uh we can see if we have the
latest we should have the latest I'm
thinking
[Music]
uh you wish to set track information so
me you can do this with set up
stream I thought I did that
already I guess
not
Origins
modernized this is I don't do this very
much
obviously wait what did I miss
wait why is it doing
zet because my fingers are typing
it it's not doing t-u oh you're not
t-med in
okay yeah I screwed up I I needed uh
another wrench name there we go get pull
Mac voice isolation
nice
um so laggy is really laggy it's driving
me nuts all right let's set teams up
here
um
anyway all right what do we need to do
now so we already have we set up a
resource earlier actually is it a
resource or a tool
I think we set up a tool to set up a
mini
Cube yeah we did all right so uh this
script sets up a mini Cube environment
for prod Dev and
imp
and uh I actually don't need
this because our Harbor runs an
imp um but if you wanted to do that
you could do
that I kind of want to reuse this we we
were using the Kimu 2 driver too we're
actually going to use the kbm driver
now
um can't see my command
line oh because I'm on a different
different thing thank you for telling me
yeah I don't I don't what happened with
that let me let me fix that I'm in the
process of fixing it for you
so yeah it I these screens don't mesh up
it's kind of annoying better
yeah all right
um the only downside of that is that
when I do this just you know when I do
large it all it puts a black thing at
the bottom chops my head off but that's
how come I did that because I I noticed
that from last time
but that's
okay
um thank you for letting me know
so uh it's hard to you know run your own
studio and try to get something done
um I I don't even know that we need any
of this
here you know I feel like it's kind of a
waste I I feel like all of this step is
the way so we actually have a
requirement that everything run on B
Bash which Mac has in their infinite
lack of wisdom decided to not allow to
run um which is really sad
[Music]
um so you know I I'm G to leave this
here and I'm going to change it to bin
bash well they don't allow b bash to be
I'm sorry they don't allow b bash to be
set to bash
by you have to use a bad
one you had it from Homebrew but but
then you can't use it from a Mac no you
can't it's against security policy for
you to change bin bash to point to home
brew bash and if you figure out a way to
do it you got to let me know because I
am so pissed off about that you can't
you can yeah you just use it you use it
directly right or you use us B and B
Bash but our Kat specification says you
can't use a bash unless your bash is bin
bash the end so RPX so live
oh what is that
about uh what is rx Olive about artex
Olive well that sounds like a great name
I like it a
lot um
uher sounds like a today I learned oh
right uh what specification that I say
there's a specification that we've been
following called the Kap spec which has
it's our kind of internal thing um and I
can there's no IP related to this I can
actually talk about what our KP is
in kind of General detail and then I'll
write out uh a best practices that's
sort of inspired by it um but I mean
it's it's nothing fancy I can just tell
you in a nutshell it is that you have a
read me with certain sections in it um
I'll just in like five minutes I'll tell
you and read me with certain sections
are required um you have a build to
deploy and an undeploy script and um you
have a manifest directory uh you know
with a base and then with different ones
depending on what kind of cluster you're
putting it in um we have specific
extensions to that part based on our
infrastructure you have a resources it
has any hard-coded images you have to
have or um you know uh do images things
like that do files and you have a tools
that's got anything that you're Buble to
deploy and unoy scripts might need you
know and um and that's it so these y
files that I committed those should
never be saved to our final version I
just these are from my experimentation
earlier to make sure I could draw a
distinction between the
two um there's a set number of uh we use
a set number of um of expected um uh
environment variables so we have these
uh that we use across the board so you
can kind of make sense of the of what it
is the goal of Kap is is to create a
consistent way of installing managing
and managing kubernetes applications in
our
cluster
and the the specification is ambiguous
enough in order
to uh let certain applications be
installed with controllers others to be
installed with a Helm chart uh others to
be you know with a flatin Helm chart um
and others to just you know be to have
own installation method the biggest lack
of of the biggest second day failure in
the entire kubernetes
ecosystem is there is not a single
common way to deploy an application as
much as Helm wants to be I ranted
extensively about this you go watch my
videos about it as much as Helm tries to
call itself a package manager it is not
in fact it's actually dangerous Helm is
substantively bad for your environment
and there it it regularly violates uh
and has business logic built into the
templates the templates are regularly
out of sync in fact there's a I can't
remember this substantial kubernetes
project that had three different
installers and the controller would
result in uh a template and a you know a
footprint of of kubernetes objects
installed that were totally different
than what gets installed by the helm
chart um and this is a rampant raging
problem in the kubernetes world and I
don't think it's ever going to change so
the only way to protect yourself from
this uh is to create your own installers
deploy undeploy build from whatever the
original Upstream sources are and then
to try to stay as Upstream as possible
right I personally think that this will
always be a problem for kubernetes
because there is no standard kubernetes
is just a ification it's not even
standard so whether you use Vault or you
know any of the other ones that exist
out there it's all you know the
standardization of the applications that
get used is different across the board
so there's no way someone can create a
package uh for all those things unless
they had could cover the infinite number
of combinations that are possible for
how people have deploy kubernetes and
this this problem is not going away so
the closest thing we could two years ago
uh I came up with the team here on on
stream uh with the original
specification for the Kates app uh which
is basically just a really it's out
there somewhere so you can go find it
it's just a Loosey Goosey you have to
have this section that tells people how
to do this if you're flattening the
chart tell them how to do it like this
it was basically like here are some best
practices to save
yourself and the most recent K app that
we're using at work now has been
iterated by somebody else from the team
coming to it saying no we we want to be
able to analize some of this stuff and
so they went ahead and uh that was
that's a long time ago they that's a
very old one and um so the latest U the
latest um uh idea for this was to to add
a build to deploy and an undeploy script
which I consider doing an the original
specification but Shi away from uh for
lots of reasons including you can't
account for upgrade paths like more than
two versions right this particular uh I
already talked about at the beginning of
the video but this particular approach
uh has some pretty substantial flaws uh
when it comes to upgrading because you
kind of have to punt and have a section
in your in your read me that says if
you're upgrading more than one version
at a time do this and this and this but
the idea is that once you get your Kates
apps into this form that you just up the
change the version in the build
script um you know and you just you
check the Manifest files that results
after you run build to see what has
changed which is really great because
now you can see truthfully what the
people who design this application are
actually doing there's no hiding that
right once you flat once you flatten a
Helm chart and you compare the manifests
you know in very explicit excruciatingly
pable you know detail everything that's
changed that's going to go into your
system right and then you just undeploy
the last one and you deploy the new one
and that is that is uh a part part of
that but this whole idea of undeploy
deploy kind of has a built-in assumption
that you're just going between one
version to the next because if you do
more than that which has been the
problem I just outlined then this
assumption that you can just run
undeploy and then run deploy the new one
might not work right so let's say for
example if I was if I were to make the
Assumption here that 2.5.1 I had a chart
already made I was already had a casify
2.5.1 which I don't but if I did I would
say undeploy and that would undeploy
that Harbor potentially taking us down
in the process so hopefully a change
window and and then and then you would
say Deploy on the new one right well
that deploy
script has to know where you were and
where you're going to go and it has no
knowledge of that right so the original
specification did not have an
undeployment and a deploy for that
reason by running a deploy you have to
know where you were most ceps have to
know what version they were previously
on and since you just ran undeploy you
don't know that anymore so you can't say
I'm going from here to here if I were to
tweak the spec more and I didn't catch
this one this spec was run through me as
a PR reviewer which I approved but if I
had it to do again I would very very
clearly have addressed the idea of
incremental stuff and at that point are
you just rebuilding home right um and
and I don't I don't think we are but so
there's this implied there's this
implied thing in deploy and undeploy uh
and you got to You Know cover all those
caveats yourself and say look if you're
going if you're going to run undeploy
and then you're going to deploy make
sure you know that you're just going one
version at a time this undeploy this
deploy assume so so that's the other
thing so the other assumption is that
you're not doing any upgrading at all
that this is only for installing brand
new stuff right and that that's uh
another another issue entirely in fact I
I believe that the person made the
changes would argue that U that deploy
is assuming that you have a totally
Greenfield clear new application to
deploy uh and it's up to you to come up
with the upgrade strategy so but people
coming into this specification looking
at it might not might not see it that
way what what is the the poliy script is
statable in the terms of written against
the priv no it that's the thing it it's
not specified right it's unspecified
whether it is or it isn't and that that
that's that's part of our of our
specification that worries me right but
but the answer to that would be you
would put it in the read me you could
say note this deploy assumes an
absolutely you know zero level this
application is going for the first time
but when is that ever the case
right so uh like a database migration
well that's how that's that's what I
think if if we're going to actually have
undeploy and deploy and we're going to
codify that then yeah I think you need
to do do that I do I think I think there
is kind of this implicit assumption that
your
undeploy script should
assume you know one version under the
one that you have but the current state
is that the undeploy assumes the same
version that the deploy
is so I don't know we I I there's so I
can't I got to get done so I can't
spend too much time worrying about that
you you know what I mean um but but
that's you know that's kind of where we
are we're at this like weird place um
there's another there's couple other
things um I've actually refused to use
one of the fields here that I absolutely
hate um that snuck in without me
catching it they have a field called
application
namespace and I mean application version
and there's a very specific term called
application version in Helm uh which
points the application version but in
the case of a of a harm Helm chart
that's being flattened our team has
decided to reuse that field as the chart
version and I I refuse to do that in
this one if they want to if they want to
PR arm me and they say change it fine I
don't want to do that it's too confusing
they like if it's a Helm chart then the
application version is the chart
version it's confusing as I don't
want to I don't I don't want to do that
so I just went ahead and said fine
because there's no there's nothing in
this spec that says I can't do what I
want and I call it you know Harbor chart
postgress chart uh Rish chart now the
reason these charts are here and we're
going to immediately change this is
because the last round that I did this
um I actually started building three
installers which is no longer the case
um because we don't need that anymore
um uh let's see where is it we had it
was in a tools directory I
think VM is so laggy um it's like right
next to me I'm like lit sitting right
next
to um so I decided to kind of break out
you know Harbor Post Christian reddis
and this is based on the now defunct
assumption that postr and redus had had
have separate installers so I know from
looking at the chart uh which we's go
look at that we no longer need that
anymore we just need the one build
script and we can put it all in the same
because of the bitnami chart so here is
the flatten bitnami
chart um and another thing here we the
current version has a grap DBA on
anything with Helm in the name and let
me show you why that's a huge
mistake um because as much as this is we
don't we want to get rid of Helm doing
that would absolutely break this
chart um so again this is the the arbor
ha one
uh got a harbor job services this is the
stuff that if you if you were going to
run cctl um customize and run it again
directly or Helm apply or whatever
install it would actually create these
resources and then stick them in your uh
you know do the same thing as cctl apply
dasf apply so we're just doing that step
by ourself by putting it in a script
because we want to look at the chart if
you if you install a Helm chart without
examining the template it's going to
generate
Good Luck Good Luck
really people do it all the time but no
so a lot of people uh kind of innocently
would say God I want all these ugly Helm
labels out of here and they'll g-ba
those things
out and because they're like I don't
want any any residue of hel in my
deployment
but there are lots of reasons not to do
that first of all if you don't have a
clean way to remove those bags using
actual yaml trees rooted no trees yeah
go see my other videos about Kap and KT
and all the stuff I'm doing to do
Transformations on yaml directly uh and
safely using said and grep are not safe
and and they're just not and because you
know it might work it might
not uh and and so
yeah uh C
sud andell Helm Charles yes
mine I perfectly said perfectly said I
love that uh properl changes last time I
M with this yeah you so so if you want
to do it properly you can use YT for
that and use uh the selector query
language from YT and Json or you can
convert it to Json and you can do the
conversions using JQ um I have yet to
look at the underlying code for the YT
which is go and see if we can pass a YT
query transformation transformation
query directly to uh the thing that is
par the yaml I've written my own uh yaml
node Library helper library that we use
in production today um to do those
Transformations and it does it by
walking the yaml no tree uh in you know
very um sort of you know traditional
rooted node
tree descending kind of you know
computer sciency way but I would if
there's already a query language that
does it that's built in and that's
trustable uh I would do it there walking
a node tree with your own function might
be a little bit more problematic it's
going to be hella faster to do that so
that's why I went with the Y node tree
option I'm continuing to look through
the thing here there's the trivia
install uh that is how you tell whether
you're your uh residing images are safe
or not you have to set that up after the
fact
though um what else we got
uh let's see har there's the okay so
here we go so here's the postc crust
secret so um one of the Transformations
we're going to do I'm not doing it right
now but one of the Transformations we're
going to do is we're going to take this
uh secret right here and we're going to
turn it into an external secret that
queries uh from Vault and so during our
deploy uh our deploy will be redone to
use uh Vault Secrets don't worry about
this password by the way um these these
uh these these these pass if I were to
deploy it these haven't been deployed
anywhere so um but those are secrets by
the way those kind of things will also
trigger in a security audit uh if
they're in your files if you haven't
done something with them so that's kind
of annoying
um okay so there's all the reddest stuff
there's a hardore
stuff we have to look through all this
stuff just cause so Harbor job services
environment variables
[Music]
um it's going to take a while but we got
to Margaret all that out of
there
um and there's another secret so many
Secrets got look at that
one uh I could probably skip the secret
section kid fig Maps
yay if you don't know what yeah kues are
these are kuet uh object or resources
depending on who you
ask
um that's what there I think the most
recent official name for them as
resource so there's config map that's
just a bunch of key value pairs for
configuration
um enable aof uh disable aof assistance
uh there is a bunch of information
interesting information here in the form
of comments and and I want to show you
there's actually
one uh Helm Helm very important Helm com
that gets removed if you grap DBA it in
here I don't it might not be here it
might have just been the go Harbor chart
I don't
remember um there is an assumption about
bin bash in all the code uh that's super
important that you validate that that
you maintain
that um bin bash should be the standard
scripting language for all kubernetes
things and that means if you're going to
try to run a mini Cube on your Mac that
you make sure that it's
bash 2. whatever but I don't think that
that's a good idea I think you should
just be able to use whatever bash you
want there is
no you it does make me wonder
if our specification does not say what
version of bash we're able to
use and I am going to ask about that
really quickly on chat while I
can
um because just
just give me a second just curious
um was
there is it worth
noting The
Bash version we can use or just the one
on
I'm just asking a question about if it's
worth adding the reg the the a specific
bash version to our convention so people
know what they're coding
against that that's that's significant
because it between bash four and Bash
five you can actually use um hashmaps
and hashmaps can be kind of in be kind
of useful for templatized things in ways
that are not requiring
customize so because you can create a a
key value pair map and then use that to
to kind of write your own replacement
template thing we don't we we have a
tool that we're working on to do the
template replacement but if that's
actually one reason you would want to
use bash
P um
so uh and I don't believe it's it's
available on bash
bo
uh okay they're saying that bash five is
is the required one so I agree with that
um build things on Alpine and bsh is
what you'd use for that yeah this is but
these not in
kubernetes
um so this just to be be clear this is
not a requirement for all the containers
this is a requirement
for uh build deploy and undeploy uh
within our little katab specification
so the statement about what bash we're
using kind of implies that that you need
to run these scripts on the in our
particular case we force that these
scripts must be run from this spe a
specific system and that system has all
of the
dependencies uh including Scorpio
builda uh podman and um uh bunch of
other stuff uh the our our tool for
doing template replacement stuff like
that so so that that that's kind of a
part of that but I just thought of it by
going through the chart here um let's
see that these are all kubernetes
objects yeah these are kubernetes
objects they are for sure so that's what
reminded me of it though right
um it does make me wonder though why
would they put this in the object is
that a config map was that config map
just a script that was going to get
written to a node what was
it it is okay y so so this config map is
just a big string at the end of the day
and we don't care about that right but
that that's a that's up to reddis if
redis wants to to use bin Bash that's up
to them right the the only time that
would be a problem is if for some reason
doing cctl
apply ran these scripts on the running
platform which would never be the case
right so I just wanted to talk through
that Harbor core environment
variables
um ad with trivy
true
yeah yeah well you're absolutely right
you're absolutely right because this is
just a big screen who gives a right
when I saw the bin bash it just it just
triggered my it triggered a kind of a
relate
thing it has nothing to do with the
script though you're
right yeah
um so we have carb Cod config
Maps um har job servers name space
barlog
jobs I'm I'm I'm just trying to get my
get in my head around how they've
deployed their app if you don't have any
kubernetes knowledge this stuff's going
to look like
gibberish uh uh kind of as a a fun fact
this is why kubernetes people and devops
people are called yaml
programmers because they spent all their
Day writing yaml and learning the syntax
of a specific type of yaml depending on
the
application
um you know this is something I actually
really like about vietnami that is not
if I remember right this is not in the
harbor chart I'm going to go confirm
that right now but you see this right
here
the HTTP
proxy it actually includes this is
really key for Enterprise
deployments um
because you need to hard code these in
your
deployment
and what is this
about that is this is a bad Helm chart
you see
this that's
I got to compare that to our
deployed
version that's absolute
you see that that's an error in
the print up statement that ran from the
helm
chart you see this right here these here
I'll point at it
right
right there where it says missing right
there and right
there that that right there is bad
that's super bad this would probably
break your
proxy holy I'm glad I looked at
this Helm chart okay time for me to make
a
point boys and girls
and everybody in between you can't say
boys and girls anymore I'm sorry I'm not
trying to be
weird check your Helm charts
people check your Helm charts run your
apply if you if you mind said it
perfectly if you do doing Cube let's see
doing Helm install is the same as
curling a script from the internet to
bash without checking the
script don't do it this has been brought
to you
by
I oh my God I just can't deal with that
right now that I'm so glad I
looked all right I've got to go compare
it to our actually deployed
one um
what's it what's it what is what is the
resource uh config map okay so config
map Harbor job service
Nars
Harbor I'm checking our production
one no they're populated
they're all populated but
one one of our production ones has a
missing in
it
yep okay
now this is this is this is a tough
decision I wish I wish there was a
faster way to do this now we have to
decide do we dive into the depths of
Harbor Helm to see who up
and possibly even consider submitting an
issue or do we go our merry way see if
it actually works
anyway and let them screw with their own
stuff that they should have tested
better
anyway I don't
know I don't know I don't know what the
right answer but this is why you need to
platin it because once you see something
bad like that you can't unsee
it
God I hate kubernetes
I do I hate it I hate code period but I
hate like this i' I've gotten very
J buck up little
camper say observability
team oh God the log leaks oh God if
what I mean like 10 more I
know because there's no attention to
Quality all I get it out there
fast oh someone is sending me
something this is not
good I just got a message from somebody
I don't know
who I'm gonna make sure I'm not in
trouble or something give me a
second I'm I know I'm bu I know you're
like go get copy or something don't
complain all right
speaking of
copy did dare me to yell yell really
loud at my wife who came home early to
bring me
copy how many
bits hey
Doris it's so easy to make I just have
to push a button now the beans are in
the machine I just have to push a button
I just push be the copy comes
out oh God okay stay on task Rob um you
know why I get off task because I
hate this stuff I hate
it sorry I'm getting kind of
negative I hate Helm I hate it give me
some go code any day
maybe she's watching the stream and I
could ask her okay here we go there's
the
bug is there anybody is there a good
soul out there who wants to add like a
bug a bug
submission you know you know what's
about to happen yeah it's like I don't
want to look and I because I know it's
coming it's going to get even
worse um
um I'm putting my face here I I do like
this little presenter thing where I can
like move my hands around and
stuff that I do love I do love
that
there it's a Mac thing suei I'm on a
Linux machine V via a Mac so
they I I don't care what you think of me
all right what else we got
[Music]
um that's
fine more ciphers
embedded proxy pass SL
portal what why is that hardcoded
what is this resource it's engine X
yeah yeah okay good old engine
X we love you where where did my white
balance go I'm all red
now oh I know what it
is it's because of the light behind me
yeah I should probably turn it
off I like my light
though I like it
but it's making me
purple
so
um I I am fighting off putting this off
and going eating coffee because I
hate
it um
I don't need to debug engine X right now
har I trust Harbor on that
okay Harbor
portal
oh did that mean that they have a
service called portal I'm guessing
oh Max is
here I thought I thought Doris was here
it's just my
stepson yeah M of above
okay that's that's fine then I thought
maybe they were they were hard coding
some sort of proxy reference which would
suck
um oh these are just all internal these
are just all internals service
references DNS
names yeah so that's fine
which is like kubernetes networking is
like an entirely different species of
networking if you can know you can be
doing a network engineer your whole life
and like come to kubernetes and have to
deal with an ARP storm and go what the
hell it's it's a big thing anybody who's
a beginner they see kubernetes and
they're like oh my God I got got to
learn all that I'm like go and it's it's
not fun there's a lot of people who are
happy there's like
a twitch streamer the other day bragging
about uninstalling kubernetes from their
home lab because they didn't have to
play with it
anymore this is not an advertisement for
kubernetes in case you can't
tell I hate it I hate kubernetes
but it pays the
bills
um
wait is that hard call is that hard
hardcoded
PVC it
is oh
okay so this is something to note
we're going to have to
change um we have we're going to have to
cap a resource requests
here I'm wondering I'm wondering if
they've already bumped the
quota in our in our kubernetes
policies for Harbor because the images
are so
big remind me to look into
that I need to remind myself to look
into that
somehow
oh anyway let's keep
going
um
okay what is this resistant volume
claims uh if you're new to kubernetes
just you know persistent volume claims
is that thing right there they are how
kubernetes manages
storage and like give yourself like
three months to understand CET
storage there is no storage there is no
storage these are this is not the
storage you are looking
for okay default F
HL I'm only 41%
through you know why because this is
this
is I'm getting another somebody keeps
somebody keeps sending me stuff and I
I'm missing it I
guess I'm going to my Elites my my
things because I don't I don't want to
miss
something somebody keeps sending
something and I keep hearing
it you heard it right
okay all right
um didn't hear it that's nice hey
onion you're that onion you're not just
any
onion
um we got
PVC so anyway the reason this is so big
is we got postcrush redus and harbor in
and believe it or not we have to add
more we're going to add a postgress
backup process that uses PG dump to the
Manifest in addition to everything else
and I am now running out of power how am
I running out of power quick we need
more
power oh my
God my God I need more power I need more
power please don't die please don't
die oh no
oh I forgot to plug it in what kind of
thing is does that I'll be right back
ah all right I'm
coming used to be I could take it with
me but now you're now it would just
unplug you if I did
that
wait all
right I got to get this is a new setup
in case you're wondering
H
know can I go get copy
now all right like do something I'm G to
put my my hair I'm gonna go make copy
I'll be
back I'll put the fishies on I can't put
music on right because it'll demonetize
the
video
what where did my advon bile
go that makes me very sad
there you
go back back in a
bit oh wait what is going
on oh that's
weird why is it so
oh I'll be back in a bit
oh
God multi streaming well actually I'm
not multi streaming I could I thought of
it I thought about multi streaming now
but
um I've just been pushing the videos up
to YouTube I should probably do the
multi stream though we should we should
probably multi stream that would be
better great idea for
she e
I do just remember that
I'm going to try to go biking at 4: so
we don't have a lot of time this means
I'm probably going to
be my wife's doing a late night
tonight uh I'll be
back means I'll be doing more streaming
later because I got I got work to finish
either that or I'll be up early tomorrow
one of the
two we need to make some progress on
this um so
anyway um
all right we got this is the kind of
thing I can just drink Coffey and read
like a Noel
so sounds still good
yeah check one two all right just
checking
um okay now this is important and in
fact and we're going to actually take a
break looking at this yaml and look at a
different yaml really quick we're going
to look at the the harbor go Harbor yl
and see if there is this let's actually
open up
to um let's call this one is this
uh that
Amo
and um why are we doing this because I
want to understand the differences
between them I don't know why I just
do
um so here we go this is the TCP this is
we starting to get into the postr stuff
right so let's call this
one
[Music]
um uh B
Meo so we have we have the two charts
and I want to see where the charts
divert from one another that is the
substance of distance and
I my memory my memory is correct
this uh this here does not exist in the
other
one so Harbor postr I could be wrong
though so that's what we're about to
find out so Harbor
postgress nope I was right okay I feel
better about myself just let's more all
right so why does that
matter why does that matter uh I'm going
to make a point again here's the point
making screen the reason this matters is
because as the instructions say for
Harbor if you want postgress H Harbor ha
that means you need to install postgress
by yourself if you saw the previous
video where I was trying to do this that
is why I started writing a basically a
mini Kates app for postgress
installation that was embedded into the
build script and I wrote three build
scripts one for postr one for redis and
one for Harbor because I needed to get
the Manifest file so then I could apply
those and do the magic there but as you
can see the bit namami chart for the
same exact version has postgress has a
harbor has a harbor Das
postgress data object met it you know
kubernetes object and the go Harbor
chart does not that is really important
and for those of you who know kubernetes
you know exactly why it's important um
because it just doesn't exist
it's like so so here we go so again this
year had I seen that earlier had I known
that that was in the original bitnami
chart and I could get somebody could
yell at me for not using that because
that's what they we're using now right
now we're using the bitnami chart and we
have a post just like this but it's
disabled it's disabled for whatever God
knows what reason I think it was because
we were trying to do something different
and have it be completely independent
the resolution of the team now is now
just just stay with Upstream don't cross
the streams get it I haven't drink
coffee
now so what this means is
that we're going to pay really close
attention to the next little section
here and this is why this file is only
42% long down here that's what this is
is because it's got an entire postc
crust deployment built
in yeah you'd have to write all that by
yourself or you'd have to go to postc
and find some the vietnami chart for
postgress which is I think what we did
before I think so anyway so there's
postgress it's all in
there um one of the reasons to do this
of course is because you know the idea
is the postrest that's that's that's
shipped with uh the helm chart has been
tuned um to work well with Harbor which
it was not in the previous
versions um here we go Harbor redus
headless so
this also has an embedded redus and I am
going to make a bet here that there's no
such
thing uh as a redus in here at all nope
in fact the only redus in here is the
thing that says hey go use redus over
there there's nothing that builds redus
into kubernetes or deploys the
kubernetes there's just the database
saying hey use redus right it tells you
what Redd is pool to use and everything
but if I remember right there is nothing
in this entire Helm chart oh wait there
is I take it back there it is right
there did I just miss the post press one
too this is super important I gotta I
got to really be sure on this point
because this this this this information
is influencing the decision about which
chart to use and that's a Hu it's a big
big deal because that that's that's like
you're codifying what Upstream you are
dependent on and that is very very
important if you're an Enterprise it's
super important because it actually
turns out to be money did I type it
wrong all right
post
post is it in here nope no pattern no
pattern found for post god damn it
I'm an
idiot oh
maybe it isn't here and I was
wrong I
know I
yeah okay so there's all the code to do
the post
thing
uh I searched for Harbor Post I bet I
misspelled it
I'm just searching I'm scared now so I'm
just searching for postc while I have it
typed correctly until I find
it nope that's it all right I was
right stream is buffering
hard oh
no why is the stream buffering
hard why is it buffering
hard it's buffering for me too
yeah yeah it is it's definitely
buffering for me
too there's something going on with the
computer I must have broke
something yeah I was afraid of that oh
you know what it's the low power thing
that's what
yeah you see my power up here
um I
mean how much time we
got getting the power this is
really Max is that
they they they do not
like low power even though it
say
um I don't know I stream though because
put a
hole that's that's issue right now I'm
on really really low
power more power
so
e e
free do you know how hard it is to have
a full-time job and still
stream and go biking and stay healthy
and everything see look at how much
faster it is
now see
that it's gone right
is it working for you
now it is right it's much better I'm
from what I'm saying it's much
better I got you some more
power nobody's answering maybe they
can't hear
me they're they're gone they're totally
gone let's go
see let's go see if they're there
no they just like they already
left they're all
gone check one
too it's still lagging how come it's not
lagging for me
now now it's not
lagging last couple of minutes garble
up audio and low frame
rate
what it says my bit rate is still fine
though you refresh it's been
fine
um did it finally turn smooth for you
okay I actually I I I'm at fault it's my
fault my bad I let the power get low and
I just plugged it into high power in the
highest possible power it can be plugged
into
so um if you're on YouTube I'm sorry you
can hopefully you fast forward pass up
part
um and I think I am going to start
streaming YouTube Okay so we've only got
20 minutes left so let's try to get
through this
file
um it was like a minute behind
really I don't think it is now I think
it's caught up I I think it was the
power
thing um if if not I'll just stream from
something else just let me know we I
have a machine that works to stream from
that Windows machine I just put
something else on
there
yeah I think you guys have talked me
into putting Linux back on my desktop
for streaming
although if I do that then I can't do
the little bubble thing we're good now
okay um note to self don't let the power
get low all right so we have postr on
here and we don't have postgress we just
have postgress calls in the go Harbor
version of the
chart uh but in
the uh in the in the bitnami version
and the guys who are you know I can just
hear them in my head they're like yeah
we already knew that and they would be
right but I need to understand what's
going on here was I'm porting it I don't
I'm I have to know that's just how I am
but look at all this postc stuff
man it's all it's got tons of post up
so we can get through the postcrush
review let's review that postcrush
stuff uh
wait what how is this at the top of the
chart oh that was just a pod
distribution budget what okay so see
this right here this pod distribution
budget stuff right here let me show you
let me point my finger this P this stuff
right here is
awesome is
awesome it's awesome I say this one's
more fun
this this right here is awesome because
this
means
that the people who put together this
chart have already thought about po
distribution budget stuff they've
already thought about performance and
management and how Harbor is going to
how how post is going to be integrated
into the harbor deployment and um I mean
that's not you know particularly sexy
all by itself but the fact that it
exists means that um there's been some
thought about how all this stuff is
going to play nice together in the same
Harbor name space all this stuff by the
way is living in the same name space so
right now it's all in the default
because I didn't set name space when I
flattened it but that will change it to
Harbor So This postr And redus and
harbor and engine X and all that are all
going to live in the harbor Nam
space all right so so
there uh we're down to 12%
here metadata name stend configuration
it's only 20%
down okay this is the one that we were
looking at
before HL what is that about headless
okay postr headless interesting oh it's
the service so this is the Headless
postc service
okay yeah
um there's a harbor postcard service
I see that you know what something else
they did when they organized this chart
which is kind of interesting um they
organized a chart based
on object type kubernetes resource
object type
and so you have postr stuff
intermingled uh with the other the
engine X and register stuff I don't know
if I like that really doesn't
matter
um is important what
uh resarch requests and stuff to find so
to try to figure out what are the
requirements with yeah oh hell yeah I
hear you
um
so so you see here's reddis headless and
here's postgress this is what I'm
talking about so here's Harbor postgress
I'm betting you this is Harbor postrest
HL Harbor registry they those are that's
the bond claims never mind I'm pretty
sure all the services are right next to
each other so this is a service this is
a service this is a service I guess
that's
fine security live what's up how are you
doing um we are just
uh trying to stay happy going through a
Helm
chart thank you for the raid everybody
yay
um and uh yeah I'm on AAC so what
suei
um but I log into a Linux
machine um I'm using I'm sorry I'm using
the largest Unix distribution in the
world how about that is that better
thank for being here Raiders um where
trying to caught up by a a harbor
installation and we recently made
significant discovery about the go
Harbor which is listed on the website
being different than vietnami chart the
vietnami chart includes redis and postc
cross if that's all borign to you I'm
sorry um this video will be up on
YouTube as well it's kind of a
co-working video I me trying to get
Harbor going and write this build
script uh we're in software and Deb by
the way category because we are writing
code at to some
degree um we got engine X we are still a
long way from through this
file an iOS game on Ma
nice yeah I stream for Linux for two
years and I got past all the screen
ripping and all this that it's bad
with Linux desktop then popos the
bed went black screened on me I had to
ssh in remote system to get my computer
back and then I couldn't Whi on my
machine
anymore and so I went back to Windows
and put a put a 8 gab BM on
there so I can play my zift but now I
have a now I have a couple Mac laptops
so I can run my zift on my laptop when I
want and stream it and I'm G to I've all
but decided to like install um Linux
back onto my primary my primary
streaming machine the only downside of
that is the streaming software for IRL
stream some of it is Windows specific
believe it or
not
so uh Y is technically code good
point um job service
Helm po Affinity all that what is
this oh wait there's some resource
constraints right
there what is this automatic SE dist
automatic seert
renewal what is this
Harbor job service
interesting I don't know what that is
it's a harbor
thing Harbor has a concept of a job
interesting well there is okay so this
is actually one of the reasons I wrote
the the yaml node tree uh Walker because
I wrote a I wrote a oopsie
develop f with Docker how about
no how about we never look at Docker
again ever
um so this right here this is not in
this one because this is a registry
itself we don't have to write the
translation code uh but normally I would
be walking in the tree and looking for
any key that says image and
changing uh deleting the registry and
stuff and I actually have code that I
started in my yaml no Tre parser that
does that
uh that translates the image uh
tags so because this a really common
thing um container scabs and jobs
really LBG you know what you were
helping me with a project before next
time I do a stream if you see KT in the
name the kubernetes
toolkit um I really would like to have
you there it would be fun if you wanted
to help commit to that what it is is
it's a it's a it's a go monolith um and
I'm deciding to do it in Cobra just for
compatibility with with what I'm doing
at work it's the only reason and it
includes things like this like globally
finding and replacing all image keys and
if they begin with Docker change them to
something else reliably using yaml node
recursion but that's just like one
little thing that it does it does a
bunch of stuff that's related to
kubernetes Transformations and and
mostly uh transforming yaml data after
it's been flattened with customized or
yaml template or cctl template anyway uh
if if you're interested at all in any of
that I'm sure you probably have some
great ideas what it honestly what it
mostly is is it's a collection of a
bunch of you know shell Python scripts
that do different things uh not
particularly
safely um is that the new helmet no but
it's designed to have enough Tools in it
so that you can deal with platin Helm
charts in a way that's missing from from
other things
um just want you to say that because we
are just on the verge of putting our own
Templar in there because customiz
doesn't cover all the
bases and we were we're really closely
seriously thinking about having a
generic uh goang templating tool that
could do its own replacement so like if
you you could flatten you could flatten
the customized templates and then make
your Replacements and then put them
through your own but at that point
you're you're starting to diverge really
seriously from
upstream and image space
values the reg yeah but the problem is
you can't set it on everything
everything that refers to image
including config Maps can't be changed I
don't think I mean that would be nice if
that's it also differs I mean we we have
a need for globally chasing any
reference to a specific image to
something else
um you know particularly the registry
name uh and another thing we have
another tool that extracts all the image
names and sticks them in a file I know
so Helm right uh yeah but not as
bad
um
yeah I mean so one of the one of the
tools that's not Helm related would be
to dump every single container image
that uh a Kap uses like everything from
here uh as a simple way to do that would
be grip right what are we 58% so who did
this who did uh grip image from here you
see all those images right
and
uh just open a
PR
um yeah I can't I wish that was part of
our our working process we can't do that
maybe I need to talk about that but so
this is actually a pretty common thing
right so a pretty common thing when
you're bringing a when you're installing
a kab we cannot pull anything from
external so like got to be all
internal except except in this case in
this case with the registry which is the
thing into which we're going to put all
the other stuff uh it's got an exception
so we can actually put proxy references
uh sock proxy references and pull
through htps proxy and pull the uh pull
the images uh via scopio into
uh uh a new you know normally we would
pull those into a new registry right in
our case we're pulling these directly
and sticking them right into kubernetes
without any vetting at all which is
normally a bad thing to do I it's
there's this like a chicken in the egg
problem with with all of of um of
kubernetes in my
opinion um On's to Infinity yeah
uh it picks up strange TOS it doesn't
block my work yeah I mean that's really
the the problem with
it um so here's an interesting one this
one's pulling from the image from go
Harbor DNS
so um so yeah so that's that's all
good oh wait that change oh I'm looking
at the Go Harbor yl and this one's the
benami yl
interesting interesting so the the
harbor project offici moved all of its
images wait is there a girl Harbor
reference in
here oh my
god well we're we're using the bitnami
one because it has postor redus built
in and but Harbor has generally changed
over to go Harbor and because they don't
want to use Docker and all the images
from bedami are pulling from
Docker if you know any reason at all I'm
serious if you know any reason at all
not to use the bitnami chart like maybe
it's two out a date I need to know that
because that means we have to write our
own postc crust and Rus
installer and or flatten or you know
basically c saify those two things in a
way that will play nice with Harware uh
because they are not in the go Harbor
yaml we just compared we compared the go
Harbor yaml the bitnami and uh reddis
and postc are not installed in the go
Harbor stuff the vietnami stuff actually
installs it
so as of this moment because our current
system uses the vietnami chart and use
and is now going to use it to to do its
uh the post
installation so so yeah
um but this is this is one of those
questions right you think that would be
an authoritative source for the the
chart there's
not hey was
your um
we're at 59% through here we're going to
try to get through before four when I'm
going to go
biking um
so uh what is this or PVCs okay the
actual engine ex deployment I don't need
to know that I trust them on
that
um so I think we're getting near to the
end here the harbor portal
what is the portal oh this is the thing
that we were referring to the other day
Okay this is their front
end
right
okay um OBG are you guys still using
Helm charts are you one of the groups
that flatten I can't
remember last time I was doing all this
stuff uh I think I think por ofil said
that they they are required to make
everything into a Helm chart
and they also said they worked for a
really large Investment Bank that their
process was everything must be a Helm
chart you guys you remember that debate
from a year ago or so I'm just wondering
if you remember because because
that um there were a number of other
people from you know CTO level kind of
people that were talking or you know
senior engineer Architects they were
talking about their strategic Direction
with regard to helm and a bunch of the
rest of them are saying to flatten
including tny fa Tony PA said definitely
flat and Helm don't play with Helm Helm
sucks but then there are these other
conservative companies and you P saying
that they their their processes
everything must be home they also must
they also must check the any container
before they have air gaap dis kind of
containerization of everything you
cannot put you cannot bring images in
and then after the fact trivia scan them
you have to check them in advance before
they get added
and hey Ray so we're GNA we're going to
be on the bike here in a bit I've got to
I'm going to probably take a little
longer than usual to get on the bike but
um yeah Els tried like customize oh you
tried customize you know what's funny
they snuck customize in on me I I did
not want to use it I'm trying to give
customized the benefit of the doubt now
in our Standard Process they now depend
on
customize and
and I am
like you know we use customize but yet
we still have bash code basically making
a template and replacing values and I'm
like and I asked the question I said can
we do this with customize and they're
like no customized doesn't do that it's
not in that realm so we need yet another
template language I go yeah here's the
one I built on my own personal site I'm
like we can't use some random template
engine that you made it's like and and
that does bring up the question like
we're going to be templa izing things
again because we were dealing with
flattening complex stuff and like where
are we not just using Helm correctly and
redoing the helm chart like bami has
done from the official stuff from go
Harbor right or or is there something
about customized I don't know because I
don't want to have five different
template engines in our different Kates
applications you know what I'm
saying um
so I I don't know I mean at what point
do you start to start to pun I don't
think you should ever do a home install
the fly I just don't think you should do
that I think every single person should
flatten their template look at it and
then most people aren't going to be able
to do that anyway because there is no
concept of backing up postgress right
that does not exist in the harbor chart
template if if you if you go to the go
Harbor template the go Harbor Temple
doesn't have any concept of postgress
period you have to write a kesap or you
have to install and manage a postgress
which is essentially a kesap by
encapsulating all that into a go into a
get repo for postest right and in
addition to that you also have to come
up with a backup process which we have
codified we have our own way of doing
that we have a config map and we have
you know uh kubernetes Crown job that
runs and regularly PG dumps do
particular PBC and and that stuff can
all be restored at some point and I'm
going to do that here as well but that
backup of
postgress belongs in my in our in my in
my way of thinking if it's a part of our
Harbor installation it's a part of the
just the post cross instance that's
going with Harbor that backup process
that backup deployment you know
kubernetes deployment all the pieces
that go into it those need that stuff
needs to also go into the Manifest along
with the you know and it would go get
listed under customized under our
resource listing and then we would we
would say okay here's here's here's you
know all the yl to do our the stuff that
we wrote uh to back up post which is our
own customization uh here's you know
let's actually let's actually look at
the customize by the way so if we look
at the customization stuff we look at
our resources I'm sorry
manifests we have the base customization
so app. yo and then we're going to have
um uh PG
backup.
yl and
um yeah if you really want production
deployment I would use redus and post
operators that's what everybody keeps
saying and um the answer is that
no because because boy look what happens
when we need to upgrade our version of
Harbor you
know in a perfect world so okay this the
reason that I okay this is actually a
really poignant conversation because the
reason that I am going with the postr
it's embedded the reason we've decided
to do that is because of like this
that I'm going to show you if you go
through and go look at the upgrade path
right if you look at Harbor
Administration and you look at the
upgrade path let me show you some of the
dangers of not using the built-in thing
and um configure project quotas blah
blah
um installation process Harbor
components High availability with Helm
we did
this reconfigure troubleshooting Harbor
where's the
upgrade uh the upgrade one the upgrade
one says you have to have version 10 and
postest versus some other version so the
the danger the risk is that you would
end up
not getting I mean let's say that you
want to go from one version to another
and your postgress is downgrade down
level then you obviously have to you
know write an an upgrade to your
postcript that whole all that work would
have to take place outside of the scope
right if it is it under Administration I
thought it was under there I was there
wasn't there
anyway um upgrade Harbor and migrate
data so here you you must use version 10
again you must back up your data in
Harbor 2.9 using external dat to make
sure you're using post greater than 12
see
this okay so this is what I'm trying to
talk about there there's another warning
I think between 25 and six that's or
seven and eight I can't remember that
says you have to have version
10 so the the the the use case here the
working you know I don't know the
workflow is I want to go from this
version to this version this version
right and you want to reduce the amount
of downtime and outages and everything
like that right and you have a number of
choices to make about how you deploy
your Harbor and one of the choices if
you use a bitnami chart is to use the
embedded postgress that comes with it
that means that when you undeploy it if
you take it all the way out of your
system andoy a new one you get the
version of postgress that gets installed
with the chart so this is actually
interesting let's go ahead and see if we
can work for that uh current is 15 yeah
but see the problem but that's not the
issue the issue is how did you get there
right and if you're what I'm trying to
say is if you are managing postest
completely independently and entirely on
its own and you only want one version of
postest versus saying I want a highly
customized version of postris that's
been tailored to work with Harbor
because Harbor sucks ass at using postc
cross ha and earlier versions I know
that because we had a problem with it
then you have the issue right you have
the issue of like what do we do how do
we do that and so if there is an option
to encapsulate a version of postgress
and a version of redus so that they are
hand inhand compatible with with Harbor
as it steps up by each version then I
don't have that problem at all I don't
have an independent upgrade path for
postgress and God forbid I have anything
depending on that version of postgress
you see what I'm saying could can I mean
this idea initially it seems like a good
idea to have a separate version of
postgress right and a separate and a and
a version you know and and your Harbor
you're like oh we should never have
those things together but then you start
to run into the problems because the
whole idea of having an independent post
oh I'm going to have these other things
use it as well well now you've locked
yourself into a specific version because
now your other applications are
dependent on a specific version of post
potentially they shouldn't be but you
know maybe and then what and then you're
try to upgrade you want to upgrade we
had this problem with some other
applications in our kubernetes cluster
that actually kept our cluster back
level by several years because it wasn't
they couldn't even do the latest
kubernetes so the best practice in my
opinion is when possible embed and and
and that is what we are doing with our
Harbor
deployment uh as switching the image PG
operators Implement that for you yeah
but that's that's an oversimplification
because um yeah I operators can be a
mess I mean I'd have to give it some
more thought but I I don't I like
operators better than hel for sure but
operators can also cause problems
because you have to give them all kinds
of permissions you have to deploy them
the right way it depends on what you
mean by operator too some people have
been using the word operator to refer to
a command that they run from the command
line that you know does all the right
things and creates the crd for this
stuff um hey bran uh like this we we can
maybe chat for five minutes in Discord
not not right now but at some point we
could probably do that yeah that'd be
great um I as of this moment though I
need to make some decision because I'm
at at work and I need to do this for
work and our path going forward um
unless there's some really substantial
evidence not to do this is to use the
chart from vietnami that includes
postest and rdus and what I would like
to do right now is to see what version
in the bitnami chart is actually
hardcoded so um I want to see what
version of postgress um that we
on so postgress version 16 version 15 in
here um if I were to flatten the chart
uh from bitnami for 2.5.1 I imagine it
would probably have version 10 or
something in there let's actually try
that um I'm I'm really curious to see
about that um what is it command of
platin again so
qctl no Helm
template
um is it list
versions wait what I don't have Helm on
here wait
what oh I'm on
Anon I thought I already install hel on
there guess
not um
want
to I made an installer give me a second
I gotta quit here in a
bit uh your your kitty your kitty
cats is that a good
thing
um oh my God I hate this
thing it's still
home I'm not using a you
know helmet which
Helm all right so let's do that again
Helm home uh what is it what is the
command I don't have time I we have to
do that another day I I'm supposed to go
biking at four o'clock but I do want to
have a conversation with you about this
um but yeah I'm not I'm not saying it
wrong I just I just don't today I don't
have time to go through it we've decided
to keep all the pieces together as best
we can because it's it's easier to
manage that
way
um so hel
template list versions I think that's it
no that's not is it is it search I think
it's search this has got the craziest
command
line no it's um that's not what it's not
it's not search what am I saying it's
repos is it Helm search or hel repo
search
um yeah I definitely want to do it
though
bash
um all right home what is it um list
releases uh God I can't remember the
command
um is a
search uh bit Nami I might I might not
even have the chart here because it's
uh I don't think I have
it okay
how
uh God what is it I can't remember my
commands I don't do him all the time I'm
wonder
eany why do I have two of these by the
way because I'm a bad programmer that
would be
right bad programmer no biscuit
[Music]
um
uh I want to list all the verses I had
Coach B this already written I put it in
my KT
thing I already have the vietnami stuff
so
um actually
images
wait
um
go why is this why is there nothing
here svm's killing me
man I gotta get out I'm going to put
Linux on there I'm going to start
streaming from Linux instead
I'm going to put Linux on there so I
don't have to deal with the VM
uh hel search repo that's
it that's it I couldn't
remember all right
so now we could oops I just did
everything uh B
let me turn the St
pulse oh wow that's
cool
[Music]
um okay so
chart actually it's going to do the
latest automatically I don't want latest
I want
[Music]
um uh template
uh for bitam
Harbor
version I could use my KT
tool I could use my KT
tool I don't have the reverse version
though I actually want that even though
the on it said it it wasn't useful
I think it could be useful and to look
up what chart version goes with what
version I wrote that code and I deleted
it all because they made me feel
bad like that's not that's not accurate
if you you can have multiple charts are
listed for that one I'm like that's
probably true so just list them all
right that version anyway um but there's
always there's exactly one app version
for each chart version though but the
reverse is not
true hel crap I know I I was going to do
that but I don't want to do
that
uh okay fine I was trying to find the
image for the specific version I want it
to be specifically
2.5.0
um
anyway actually I think I just answered
my own question
grip uh
2.51 yeah look at them
all hate
grap that's not going to find
anything I need word
boundaries PC
grab these are Pearl only
things I was going to do that too
yeah
um oh
whoopsie uh bit Nami
haror I know don't laugh at me I
suck so yeah you you can't use you can't
use the be unless this PC reg
GP you know that's like word boundary
it's only Pearl that's not in if you
guys don't know a little note about
regular Expressions there's basic
enhanced uh
PC and whatever the hell no gawk knock
and O do which is doesn't follow
anything at
all uh that's why Pearl was created in
Pearl one Pearl PE regular Express pcre
is supported in every modern language
including go python
rust the end so that's why I'm using p g
because I know it and the regular
expressions are consistent and they will
work in any
language it's probably not worth it to
take over your grip with pcre grip
because the grip that's out there won't
work grip built-in GP could either be
enhanced Reger expressions or basic it
depends on how your system was built
which sucks ass and that's why Pearl was
invented that is the reason Pearl was
invented I'm shaking my finger stop
saying about
Pearl rip grip
is not something I would
use Daryl how was that how' I do okay
so I don't want to talk about it
uh I know I know people are going off on
riger Expressions now in the chat you're
gonna have to join us on Twitch and and
eventually YouTube I'm going to start
restreaming to YouTube so YouTubers you
can join us live very
soon not right now
though all right
um should we should we restream to
Facebook no bad idea
LinkedIn no just YouTube and twitch
that's good okay never mind um what was
I looking for I I want to see if the
postest version before we end this
stream and I'm late for my other stream
and I got to change my clothes and
everything get in my bike
gear somebody be here without check it
in um before we leave this this video
though I want to see if the 2.5 version
of Harbor in the bitnami chart accounts
for the fact that it needs postgress it
can use postest under version 10 we
already saw that the latest version of
the bitnami chart for 2.1 Harbor uses
mandates to use and includes you know
all the code necessary to pull down the
image for postgress 15 which is one of
the latest okay yes we're about to
download the chart and look in the chart
that's exactly what we're doing I just
want to make sure to get the right chart
and so in order to do that we need to
get um uh people are vaccinating a
little bit on this I appreciate it um so
we're going to go do a bit template
command Helm template I hate that I'm
having to learn TM over again Helm over
again I hate Helm sorry for this
s word Helm template
um
uh bit Namy I suck I know I suck I'm
sorry hey but but Helm template vietnami
Das Das version I had to look up the
chart version for 2.5.1
uh which apparently there are
several why would there be more than one
chart I don't
understand I really don't understand
that oh so they made improvements to the
chart that were independent from the
improvements to the app version okay now
I get
it I now I get it actually this is
interesting because for my K2 tool what
I want to do is I want to I want to
return the the highest version of the of
the chart that for a given application
version and I want to put that into a
command because I don't want to have to
do all this again I want to be able
to have a command I can just do this uh
stay tuned for that that'll be a go
programming uh stream some
point uh should be an independency sub
chart yes so uh we're going to do 14.0
point2 and we're going to dump that to
uh
Harbor uh bit on
me uh
Dash uh
25.1 um actually no do
14.02 because my KT command already can
look it up let me show
you uh I'm sorry I'm going to show you I
don't care if you don't want to know I'm
going to show you
anyway go and install
CMD
at and I haven't done anything on Anton
yet
so so now we can do this we can
do um
KT tab tab
whoops exac bash DL did I I don't think
my bash has been updated it hasn't oh
God this is going to be so
ugly please don't break please don't
break it worked oh my God
God uh exac bash dasl KT space t what
the hell my completion is not in there
yet did I must not have committed it to
my do files on the other system
anyway
um uh
KT polition
bash hey tab tab there we go uh Home tab
tab at BIR
uh I don't
remember oh there we go chart and
version
so the chart
is uh bit
Nami uh
Harbor app version 4 and just to do the
reverse test on this 14.0 point2 that
should give us 2.5
2.5.1 okay good my tool works all right
so um so let's do
that
um right so so let's go look at the
heart number B numy
stuff and we should see the post
actually uh grip this is you know lame
actually
we could do a search for that using YT
but I I'm not good enough yet with the
query language for YT to do that um grip
search what am I what am I doing
grip uh
image look at that actually let's just
look for the Post
one
don't yell at me
it's saying 15 oh I doubt it no it's
13 so so that
means uh if you used the bitnami charts
and you enabled the postrest install
which you can disable we disabled it in
our bitnami chart there's a true false
yaml flag you can use um that postgress
version 13 would be
installed as a part of the harbor
install and again I'm making the point
that there's a decision to be made and
and LBG is is arguing the opposite Point
uh which is totally valid which is do
you want to keep postrest separate from
Harbor as has been documented by the go
Harbor project or do you and then you
know upgrade them on their separate path
but make sure that their dependencies
are in line as you do so
or uh you use the bitnami approach would
squishes postgress redus and harbor into
a single uh deployment it's application
is kind of thing and then do those um it
is old it is old it doesn't matter it's
like you know it's it's like when apps
when you thinking about package AP
packages and things like that you're
thinking about you know how old they are
there the thing to keep in mind is that
sometimes the newer version is not
compatible with a previous version and
and that can create dependencies um our
team's decision is to move to the all
encapsulated Harbor with postr redus
built in and because of this migration
maintenance uh dilemma is being able to
because the idea is is that if Harbor
upgrades if there's a postgress upgrade
they need they'll put it into the
vietnami chart automatically
and it'll pull a different image and
postgress will be taken down and rebuilt
and that postgress that's being built
with Harbor will have absolutely no
dependency ties to any other application
in our environment and that idea of
encapsulation uh is largely why
kubernetes exists and um in my opinion
and trying to maintain a separate
version of post and a separate version
of Reedus and a separate version is more
of an old school way of managing
services within the Enterprise and one
of the reasons for the kubernetes idea
of being able to put all these
dependencies together into a single
package it's not but is so that at an
Enterprise level you can upgrade
everything at the same time without the
interdependencies that have come to
plague us uh over the years because we
you know were waiting for a certain
version to be there or not so so that's
the
idea uh PG is 13 November 2025 yep which
is which is one of way the reasons we're
getting off it's also highly insecure
there's a bunch of security issues with
the current verion of postcards that we
have deployed um and even though we're
behind a bpn um that's one of the
primary drivers for that so I think
that's probably a good good way to um
yeah but this is 2.5.1 I deliberately
pulled up that version for that for that
purpose LBG did you not see that part I
wanted what I wanted to do is I wanted
to make sure they're on 2.15 for the 2
.1 Harbor you see what I'm saying I
wanted to see if they were back level in
that other one and they are right so
which is yet another I'm glad we I'm
glad we did this because this is yet
another reason the way that we were
going to do this is we were going to
port and I was going to make a Kap for
2.5.1 which would have been a huge
mistake and then the idea was we would
eventually you know Step Up all the
versions one step at a time and get all
the way to 211 but then we sense and I I
summarize this the reason for this at
the beginning of the video but but we've
we've since decided to jump all the way
to 211 and to to instead of migrating
the data have people enter new data into
the into the new system for lots of
reasons including the fact that we're
going to have a new cluster anyway with
a new authentication scheme that they
already have to authenticate to and
there's a bunch of dead data uh uh in
the old one so so that's it uh but
Vietnam
chart yeah the latest chart that's we we
saw that maybe you missed that I looked
at that right I got I got copy and stuff
but we we actually looked at that one uh
specifically so let's graph images
um uh from Harbor
vietnami uh the vietnami
one and then let's uh grab post rest and
you'll
see so that you'll see that's on
1.15
so what
what did I spell it wrong I
again where's wind to make fun of me
again okay that doesn't make me happy
there we
go what wait a
second
oh hold the phone
here hold the phone I swear I saw
version 15 in there
oh my
God I this is going to
be oh my God
this is such a big deal you
guys
um I'm pretty sure there are two
versions back
yeah
oh
God this entire 90 minute video or two
hour video has been worth
it I 15 is the version I was expecting
to
find but I'm not see
it there is no postest version
in in in the go Harbor
project at
all because they did that on purpose
they said you need to install your own
version this really really changes
things I mean this is really significant
I am really glad we found this this is
going to
directly change the conclusion that my
team has made up to this
point
and the decision is very simple it's a
hard decision but talking about what the
decision is is pretty
simple so 16 is the latest right
so here is the decision do you stay do
you use the the documented way by the
way that's a little tough to quantify as
well because both using bit nomy charts
and the go Harbor charts are both
documented as being the way to do it on
the Harbor website they haven't fixed
that
yet so now the question becomes it
appears to me that the harbor project
just said look we don't want anything to
do with postgress and redit if you want
to use it go do it and we're going to in
our chart that we're going to support
we're not going to have anything in
there about it you just need to make
sure you have at least this version and
they put big black warnings everywhere
right here make sure you're on version
12 right in this case is
2.11 so the bitnami charts have decided
to go with postgress version 13 and
postest version 14 15 16 are out and yet
the charts have not been updated for
those different versions of
postgress um and yet version 13 and post
Crest is going to be end of life next as
as LBG said next year in 2025 so if
we're going to go through all of this
work to do this upgrade and then find
out that bitnami doesn't decide to
upgrade their postest dependencies and
13 gets end of life and they haven't
made this really pretty you know
encapsulation of postest in the harbor
chart for us to use now we're screwed
because now we we we you know we've
hitched our we've latched our cart to to
the vietnami horse and it we we
dependent on bitnami updating it so
here's the decision the decision that my
team has to make and potentially your
team has to make is do we manage our own
postgress sub Kates app that is
associated with Harbor potentially our
own Standalone Kates app which is more
old school that we were talking about
earlier whereas you just have a post
instance that everybody uses and then
manage this dependencies and everybody
is just using this single thing in your
cluster and then you're just reusing it
or are we going to enable uh or are we
going to build a postgress you know
kesap that goes with Harbor and have it
be in the same names space and
everything which is what we were doing
previously kind of have both so so my
team and potentially your team has to
make a
decision do we manage the postest and
Rus installations
separately from Harbor as is documented
in the most latest release of Harbor and
is obviously the way that the latest
kesap I'm sorry the latest uh chart Helm
chart for Harbor supported on the go
Harbor repo registry wants to be that's
what it wants to be it wants to be
independent it wants you to do all the
Poston redit separately they don't care
how you install it you can you know and
there's many ways to install it
obviously but they don't want anything
to do with that meanwhile the bitnami
people are like no we're going to bundle
that stuff all together we're just going
to be really out of date
so LBG I'm glad I listened to you um I
mistakenly I am so glad you asked me
about the 15 thing because I swear to
God if you go back in the video I think
what I did is I saw another image that
had uh 15 in it and I
mistakenly Associated that with
Harbor um
whoops I'm pretty sure that's what I did
in fact I I I'm just going to check
myself here um there was definitely a
doer image someplace that had 15 and I
think I I think I saw the wrong thing so
I'm really glad I looked at it
again
um why can't it
find adap
Co Maybe not maybe I'm just seeing
things maybe it's a different image or
something
I could have swore I did that
though
yeah post Crush 13 they both have post
cross 13 in them are these the same
chart version did I overwrite the other
chard somehow I didn't right please tell
me I
didn't it's not trivial I yes
there it is right there
okay that's what I
saw this is just the chart version foros
foress that's what I
saw
but the PG operator will do that
for
you well what you're suggesting would be
that our even if we did it as a Kate sub
app Harbor we could use the PG operator
and build a build a like I originally
started doing we would have a build PG
and we would we would use the operator
to do that
installation and you know this this is
actually something that becomes kind of
a
problem uh when you flatten your own
stuff and do your own installations
because I have a postc crust dependency
and I want that postest do I we have to
make a decision do we put that postest
into the harbor name space if so we're
we're building an installation for postc
in a build app that could be reused for
the things that need postgress does that
make sense and then using subm modules
and that kind of thing gets kind of
complicated right but you could do that
you could make another k-
postgress um that has the latest postest
build in it and then you capes applify
that then you're not redoing that Cape
application of postgress and postgress
get to be installed with the operator if
we write all the code and we put it
under the harbor installation then we
potentially have sort of vendored the
installation of postc crust using the
operator in which case we now need to
pull it all out and put it into
something else that also needs post
crust kind of like you would if you had
a library dependency and go with
vendoring but you don't have a
centralized place for managing the kesap
for postest so this has been extremely
productive I know it doesn't feel like
I'm getting a lot of stuff done but
these are monumentally huge
consequential
decisions that can only be made at this
moment in time before we deploy to the
cluster because we are going to be
setting precedent for our other kaps and
for and you know once once we get all
our data in the new version of of of of
Harbor once we do that transition at the
end of the year into fourth quarter
that's it we we're not going to be able
to like go back right so these these
these architectural decisions are hugely
consequential and and this is why I am
streaming it because you know I wouldn't
have known that if I hadn't run a b LBG
who's got a lot of extensive experience
doing uh Enterprise level architecture
and
kubernetes um so that's exactly why I'm
on this stream this is exactly why I'm
going to put this on YouTube for those
of you who who slog through this entire
video um which I'm going to wrap up now
because I got to I got to let this
settle and this is a good top if you
want to stick around LBG I'm going to be
on the bike and we can actually talk
about while I'm bike
um if if you want to so um just as I
conclude this video um let me just recap
if you are just joining us hopefully the
video is not too weird I should turn my
light back on my light died my light
went off I have this like really cool
light here we go how's that it's kind of
too light how about down here put it
down here all right I have to have stars
and sparkles you can't be a streamer
without some fancy stars and spar Les
and stuff it's like the rule also you
need to make thumbnails like crazy or
whatever okay so here's the
takeaway we I'm going to summarize it as
best I can in like a minute and a half
if you jumped all the way to the end of
the video now is me talking and telling
you what we did okay so we went through
the charts we found up a bunch a bunch
of things we got started consolidating
the builds um we started out the day
with the intent of using the bitnami
chart that um has postcards is built
into it and by the end of the day after
a a significant amount of you know
fapping about and and looking at things
and seeing how things are done we
actually found potentially a bug in in
the helm chart uh with regard to HTTP
proxy but that's neither here nor there
um and and LBG was was pushing to use
the operator to instore postgress versus
using whatever it is that they're that
they're using in the bitnami chart and I
was presenting the argument that by
having the encapsulated dependencies you
have less work to do going forward when
you do your upgrade because they build
them into the helm chart and LBG was
making the point of well they can put
them in the helm chart all they want but
upload upgrading up updating between
major versions say between 13 and 14 and
14 and 15 is not something that you can
put in a Helm chart that is a major
major upgrade um and you might be able
to pull down the the thing we also
talked about stepping with dependencies
and data migrations and Stu like that so
we presented arguments about you know
whether you should encapsulate them all
together and contines the vietnami
charts or you should use the go Harbor
charts which don't have any reference
whatsoever to to to reddis and post
credit other than in the charts as to
how to call out to them via you know
Network calls and stuff like that so we
end the day with with a uh with a very
important decision to make and that
decision is do we proceed with the bami
chart or do we use the go Harbor chart
and then build uh essentially kaps or
subcat apps for installation of postr
and redus so that our Harbor ha
dependencies can be met right um in the
past doing that I've got a kind of a bad
taste in my mouth because the the harbor
ha doesn't have any idea how to use
postgress ha at least in 251 it didn't
uh in the process we found out that the
vietnami charts are hardcoded to version
13 of postc
including I made a mistake because the
chart number on post crust is 15 and I
saw that in the yl and I thought oh
postc crust version 15 it was actually
the chart version it wasn't the postrest
version if it were version 15 that would
have been sort of nice turns out no that
the benomi charts are still supporting
version 13 which will be end of life at
the end of 2025 LBG thank you for that
information so in fact the the most
recent release of post crust is version
16 and they're getting up on version 17
so if we're going through all of this
hassle to to to deploy uh version a new
registry into our Enterprise it's going
to have you know tons of data and models
in it that it already is using right now
we have the opportunity to make a
decision uh before end of fourth quarter
to build a a new registry properly and
the number one decision about how to do
that is whether to
include the whether to build an
independent version of postest to some
degree in the same Harbor name space or
not and how to encapsulate that um if
you watch previous videos from me about
doing this Harbor work you'll know that
I was on the path towards encapsulate
sub sort of sub encapsulating postrest
and redus and using the go Harbor chart
when I left the last time and over the
last week we had a meeting and we're
like no we want to keep it easy to
upgrade and we didn't want to have that
that separation and you know the idea
was it would be a lot faster to make to
Kate applify 2. .11 uh of Harbor not
doing that and now we've just discovered
that the vietnami uh chart has a very
old version of postgress and so I have
to go back to my team and ask them a
very simple question do we keep the
bitnami charts and have faith in them to
upgrade their version of
postgress and or do we not and do we
encapsulate with a little bit more work
do we encapsulate our own version of
postgress and and create a essentially
three k Kap deployments one for postrest
one for redus and one for Harbor all in
the same name space that's the decision
so um yeah operators usually close to
level in CDs that creates are not Nam
space I know and that is exactly why
we're not using
operators uh um yeah so I mean I'm glad
you brought that up because one of the
considerations here is if we use the
postc cross operator and this is this is
one of the reasons that people don't
like operators operators are cluster
level cluster level they create crds and
things and they can't be names spaced
that means you can't pull it out and put
another thing back in that means if you
put in postrest you're kind of doing it
old school right old school means I have
one postrest to rule them all and all
the applications shall use the postgress
right and then you have all kinds of
problems we people have dependencies on
different versions of postgress and
you're back to
1998 so this is a big conversation to
have uh and and I need need to I need to
put this forward to my group and talk
about it uh despite my extremely orange
appearance thank you for being here uh
love having you and we will see you next
time we're gonna put a bullet point in
we're going to raid I'm going to change
to get on my bike and I'll be out IRL
biking if you want to join me for that
talk more about it um so so
yeah it is a recording yep doesn't
matter though it's going to go
up yep by